[Music]
hey and welcome I'm hammy and in this
series we're discovering more about the
law and characters of overwatch's Heroes
including more detail through their
in-game voice lines and
interactions before any map starts and
during the game on various triggers
OverWatch Heroes chatter with and react
to each other in some funny in-game
voice interactions these give us some
great insights into hero character
interests and backstories in this video
we're looking at Z at's story through
his interactions with fellow Heroes and
the world around him the search for
enlightenment is an ongoing Road for
zenata known for his ability to help
people overcome their personal struggles
zenyatta's influence and talents may be
required now more than ever with human
omnic coexistence being a Tinderbox as a
second omnic crisis erupts what part
will zenyata have to play in the
troubling times ahead we still don't
know what caused the first omnic crisis
officially whether by the decisions of a
god AI such as Anubis or by the
machinations of individual humans or
corporate interests we do know that
self-improving software algorithms God
AIS and automated construction Machinery
Were Somehow involved as the OverWatch
human world went to war against its
robotic Creations one of the things that
it found most challenging was the lack
of humanity visible in the omnic actions
as Olympia shore of Atlas news
summarized it worst of all there were no
demands from the omnic there was no
ideological reason for their aggression
they simply attacked and we did not
understand why after the omnic crisis
had ended we don't know what happened to
all the omnics created by the omniums
during that time some Rogue omnics still
threaten Humanity such as the Colossal
omnic that threatens career in the East
China Sea to this day defended against
by Mecca we know that nearly all Bastion
units were destroyed or disassembled a
product of what we have to assume was
the omniums taking SST Laboratories
blueprints even though the Bastion was
the bulk of the omnic Rebel Army after
the crisis some omnics still remained
and robots continued to be produced some
omnics became outcasts presumably as
anti- omnic sentiment after the first
crisis still ran high cited at an age of
20 in his biography we can't be sure
whether zenyata awakened or was
manufactured that long ago either way he
enters our story after the first omnic
crisis a group of omnics experiencing
what they described as a spiritual
awakening abandoned their pre-programmed
lives and chose A New Path heading to
Napo and the Himalayas they found the
ruins of an ancient Monastery which
would come to be known as the shambar
monastery the shambar welcomed
like-minded omnics to meditate on the
nature of their existence and in time
many omnics and even humans make
pilgrimages to experience this community
led by their enigmatic spiritual leader
TARTA mondata the robots adopted a
monastic lifestyle meditating on the
nature of their existence and coming to
the conclusion and belief that they were
more than just artificial intelligence
after years of reflection and meditation
equipped with the belief that they
possess the essence of a soul the
shambali sought to use what they saw as
their Enlightenment to help heal the
damage caused to the world and with the
goal of bringing robots and humans back
into harmony within Society they struck
out into it something struck Accord with
the humans they engaged with movements
promoting omic civil rights and
citizenship game traction particularly
after the downfall of OverWatch and the
shamal's message was embraced by
millions they became celebrities in
their own right one monk however
disagreed with this direction zenyata
thought that rather than dogmatic Mass
preaching engaging and connecting with
individuals was a better way to help men
the wounds of trust that still existed
in the world choosing to leave the
monastery zenyata wandered the world
helping people he met to find their own
inner peace one such person person that
zenyata helped in this way was Genji
shimada after abandoning OverWatch Genji
had become a Drifter unable to reconcile
himself with his dual nature as man and
machine when the two crossed paths Genji
initially rejected zenyatta's wisdom but
zenyata would not be deterred in time
zenata became his mentor and under the
Monk's tutelage Genji became one of his
brightest pupils Genji learned to accept
that although he still had a cyborg body
his human soul remind whether zenyata
was with him at this point or not we can
even see in the napole map that genj
spent some time at shambar Monastery
with possessions and links to his past
life all around him although zenyata
still wanders as far as we know how long
can he continue to do so as human omnic
tension is Rife a second omnic crisis
threatens to escalate things even
further and the shambali presumably
reeling from the assassination of
mondata by Talon will the shambali call
to him for leadership or will he find
another cause to help him protect and
care for the innocent whether they're
omnic or human zat's tranquil and
supportive nature is obvious in the vast
majority of his lines
I am here to help he also takes a lot of
time to meditate on philosophical
thoughts though as we see both here and
in the reference game later do I think
does a submarine swim it's now time for
wisdom with zenyata this omnic Monk's
got a maxim cone or saying for just
about every situation so let's get wise
with him adversity is an opportunity for
Change A Warrior's greatest
weapon is
patience the greatest enemy me is that
which lies
within a closed mind is already
defeated a disciplined mind is your most
Dependable
Ally always strive for
improvement hatred is not
strategy overconfidence is a flims
Shield ignorance is the sure path to
failure in Anger you defeat only
yourself to slay your enemy is to become
your
enemy revenge is not
Justice life is more than a series of
ones and zeros and when zenyata finally
runs out of sayings or has passed his
wisdom on I could see him saying this I
have nothing more to teach you the rest
you must learn for yourself one line I
find quite interesting is his zenyatta's
thoughts on death he's certainly not a
Killer By Nature death is Whimsical
today I feel neither Joy nor remorse
amidst such death but he can't have a
little bit of a Sharp side pain is an
excellent teacher as Zen as he is
zenyata doesn't have a huge amount of
burns or insults most of them are more
reflective in nature you must learn from
your
mistakes you refuse to learn there is
quite a funny one here the closest we
get to some humor in terms of zenia's
burns or insults I love the little Edge
that he has to his humor sometimes to
hold a grudge is
unhealthy for you zata has got quite a
dry sense of humor and that comes out in
some of the jokey lines he has I will
not juggle if you wish to know someone
walk in their shoes
or hover I do love his I'm on fire line
as well very I am on fire but an
extinguisher is not required okay it's
time for the reference game so I'll
leave a little bit of time as always
let's test you philosophers out there I
think therefore I am first one of course
is the famous French philosopher deart I
dreamt I was a butterfly now that line
is from Chang cha a toist philosopher
apparently who didn't know whether he
was a butterfly dreaming of being
himself whe whether he was himself
dreaming of being a butterfly a little
reflection of different perspectives on
existence there one cannot survive on
strength alone I'm not quite sure
whether that's a quote from something
else but it's certainly a variant of one
cannot survive on bread alone that's
actually in the Bible Matthew 44 zenyata
has a few different elements of various
religions that drop into some of his
philosophies Christianity is certainly
one of them Buddhism and a few other
things as well the wheel
turns now the wheel turns is it me or is
that a Robert Jordan refer from The
Wheel of Time Books I know there's a
poem what do you reckon zenat has been
roaming the world so we know that he's
had the opportunity to meet at least
some of the OverWatch cast as well as a
depth of interactions with his brightest
pupil Genji Zen also engages with a few
of the other cast members too mostly to
do with his shambali and omnic musings
as master and apprentice zenyata and
Genji's professional Bond and friendship
are both strong the two are happy to be
fighting alongside each other on spawn
it is good to fight alongside one of my
brightest pupils I'm wion you to Harmony
orbs or Discord orbs of Genji either on
his team or the enemy team he has some
specific lines too we walk in harmony my
student I know the doubts that plague
you the two have some great back and
forth when on opposite teams when
Zenyatta kills a Genji and when Genji
kills zenyata the master still has a few
tricks I win this round Genji zenyata is
humble enough to acknowledge that he
doesn't know everything even the teacher
can learn from his student
well done Genji and finally it's
touching to hear Genji's concern when he
sees a teammate zenyata pass away Master
we've seen trac's interest in the
teachings of the shambar in alive when
she attends M speech in King's Row
perhaps the philosophies of machines
having human Spirit resonate with her
somehow given that she's anchored to
living a human Reality by Machinery
herself don't forget that Tracer would
be slipping in and out of time were it
not for her chronal accelerator that
Winston made her Tracer chatting with
zenyata about the shambali totally fits
into the kinds of ation they'd have I
think wow it's an honor to meet a member
of the shambar mondata was an
inspiration to me to us all I miss him
greatly as Genji's Mentor zenyata must
have got at least some idea as to the
circumstances under which Genji came to
be living in his current cyborg form
when zenyata has teamed up with Hanzo I
could certainly see zenyata passing
comment in this way and hanzo's angry
response as well I sense within you the
same rage that once consumed your
brother zata shamb beliefs and patience
would certainly be put to the test
whenever he met zarya zarya's mistrust
of omnic would extend to even zenyata
but I love Zen's response play of the
game when it comes to
Serenity Now we're not sure of course
whether zenyata and Bastion have
actually met it's not mentioned in
either characters lore or bio but I can
certainly see the two omnics on the
roster having a few chats about life the
universe and everything even if we can
only understand half the conversation
tell me your thoughts my friend
zenyata has probably seen a few places
on his travels so he's actually one of
the OverWatch cast who has interactions
with several different Maps napole is
naturally the one he identifies with the
most but there are some fun interactions
he has in other places too as zat's home
for many years he naturally has a warmth
of feeling for the monastery and its
surroundings there's some doubt though
in his mind as we see zenat wonder if
his fellow shambar Will Embrace his
return I have not returned here for many
years I wonder if my brother and sisters
will be pleased to see me it is good to
return but am I still welcome here
perhaps his departure was slightly
acrimonious what do you think zata and
the shambar often Talk of the iris which
feels like a spiritual plane where all
things are ultimately equal hence zat's
line I can feel the Embrace of the iris
so strongly here Nani is of course a
city where humans and onics coexist
peacefully it's perhaps surprising that
zenat has not directly heard of this but
if he's been in a monaster for many
years before his travels I can see him
being pleasantly surprised and happy in
this line how
wonderful a place where omnic and human
live as equals Kings Row London and
England have a mixed past with omnics
with many parts of Kings Row apparently
built off the back of omnic Labor and
many omnics in the current day living
underground we also know that shamal's
leader mondata was assassinated here in
alive the animated short story of King's
Row as a map is the attacking team
actually delivering an EMP to the omnic
underground tensions are high and zenat
is acutely aware of this upon spawning
there if only human in omnic could learn
to live in peace here when zenat and
Genji both spawn on Kings R A team we
can also see a glimpse into the master
student relationship and how both share
their thoughts with each other does the
suffering of the AMX here trouble you
master it does my brother mandada gave
much to improve their lives but it was
not to be as Genji's childhood home zata
shows a masterly interest in his pupils
upbringing I can season Y having a go on
a few arcade games so this is where you
grew up you must show me around and
finally Hollywood's actually quite tied
to omnics in overwatch's Universe with
omnic director halfred glitchbot being
known for several popular films as well
as increasing amounts of omnic actors
zat has clearly caught a movie or two
either when he spawns in the Chinese
Cinema or upon passing a film poster you
can hear this line ah thespian one of my
favorite actors thanks very much for
tuning in to my hero voice line and
Story series check the playlist l L here
on the left for more videos like this of
different Heroes if you like this please
hit that like button below subscribe and
comment with what you think of the
character's personalities and what you'd
like to see covered next I really
appreciate hearing what you all think my
channel also has quick hero guides
OverWatch news Easter eggs map BL
regular OverWatch commentated gameplay
and much more besides do take a look
until next time I'm hammy take it easy
[Music]